<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.IshuSinghSE.aurynk</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Aurynk</name>
  <summary>Android Mirroring Tool for Linux</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Aurynk is a modern Linux application for managing Android devices, pairing via ADB, and mirroring screens using scrcpy. It features a native GTK4/libadwaita interface, device details, wireless pairing, tray integration, and screenshot capture.
    </p>
    <p>
      With Aurynk, you can easily connect to your Android devices wirelessly by scanning a QR code, view detailed device specifications, and mirror your screen with low latency.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Wireless pairing via QR code</li>
      <li>Device information and specifications</li>
      <li>Screenshot capture</li>
      <li>Modern GTK4/libadwaita interface</li>
      <li>Easy device management</li>
      <li>Screen mirroring with scrcpy</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <developer id="io.github.IshuSinghSE">
    <name>Ishu Singh</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/IshuSinghSE/aurynk</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/IshuSinghSE/aurynk/issues</url>
  <url type="donation">https://github.com/sponsors/IshuSinghSE</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.IshuSinghSE.aurynk.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>aurynk</binary>
  </provides>
  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>System</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>Android</keyword>
    <keyword>ADB</keyword>
    <keyword>Mirroring</keyword>
    <keyword>Device</keyword>
    <keyword>Linux</keyword>
    <keyword>Wireless</keyword>
    <keyword>Scrcpy</keyword>
    <keyword>Screen</keyword>
    <keyword>Manager</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#f0f0f0</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#212121</color>
  </branding>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption xml:lang="en">Main window showing paired devices</caption>
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IshuSinghSE/aurynk/main/data/screenshots/screenshot-1-main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption xml:lang="en">Scanning the QR code to pair</caption>
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IshuSinghSE/aurynk/main/data/screenshots/screenshot-2-pairing.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption xml:lang="en">Screen mirroring active</caption>
      <image type="source">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IshuSinghSE/aurynk/main/data/screenshots/screenshot-3-menu.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <translation type="gettext">io.github.IshuSinghSE.aurynk</translation>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2025-11-26">
      <description>
        <p>A massive update with a complete settings overhaul, advanced mirroring controls, and many new features to give you full control over your experience.</p>
        <p>🚀 New Features</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Complete Settings Overhaul: A new modern settings window with dedicated tabs for Application, Device, and Mirroring preferences.</li>
          <li>Advanced Mirroring Controls: Full control over bitrate, max FPS, video codec, audio sources, and recording options.</li>
          <li>Instant Settings: All changes are saved automatically and applied instantly.</li>
          <li>Window Management: Customize window size and position, with handy presets for mobile form factors. Added options for always on top, fullscreen, and borderless modes.</li>
          <li>New Control Modes: Added View-only mode and OTG support for using your PC's keyboard and mouse on the device.</li>
          <li>Recording: Easily record your mirroring session with customizable formats and save paths.</li>
          <li>About Page: A new section with app information and credits.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>📈 Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved Connectivity: Device pairing and discovery are now faster and more reliable.</li>
          <li>Better Performance: Added advanced options for hardware acceleration and running without a window.</li>
          <li>User Interface: A completely refreshed and consistent user interface across the application.</li>
          <li>Enhanced Stability: Improved settings management, device monitoring, and tray icon integration.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.5" date="2025-11-24">
      <description>
        <p>Critical bug fixes and improvements to enhance application stability and reliability, including a new logging system.</p>
        <p>🐛 Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an issue causing mirroring synchronization problems.</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where the application would quit prematurely.</li>
          <li>Resolved issues with the tray menu synchronization.</li>
          <li>Fixed GPU permission issues for the Flatpak version.</li>
          <li>Added a centralized logging system for better debugging.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.4" date="2025-11-23">
      <description>
        <p>A maintenance release with documentation updates.</p>
        <p>📈 Improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated the README with new screenshots.</li>
          <li>General documentation improvements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.3" date="2025-11-16">
      <description>
        <p>Under-the-hood improvements for better performance and modern platform support.</p>
        <p>⚙️ Under the Hood</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated to the GNOME 49 runtime for better performance and stability.</li>
          <li>Switched to an inline Ayatana stack.</li>
          <li>Refreshed Flatpak and Debian build artifacts.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2025-11-20">
      <description>
        <p>Important bug fixes to improve reliability and prevent crashes.</p>
        <p>🐛 Bug Fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a crash (UnboundLocalError) when starting device mirroring.</li>
          <li>Ensured the main window and tray icon stay perfectly synchronized.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where the tray command listener couldn't be stopped.</li>
          <li>Added a PID fallback for better tray icon reliability.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2025-11-06">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of Aurynk with device management, wireless pairing, low-latency mirroring, and screenshot support for Flatpak and Debian.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </requires>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
</component>